<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-08-26T16:47:52+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nick Stares</title><subtitle>Nickstares.com: Computation, Urbanism, Education, Painting, Music, Performance.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Book Review: Way of the Superior Man by David Deida</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/2024/08/26/way-of-the-superior-man.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: Way of the Superior Man by David Deida" /><published>2024-08-26T19:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-26T19:15:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/2024/08/26/way-of-the-superior-man</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/2024/08/26/way-of-the-superior-man.html">&lt;p&gt;I picked up this book with some skepticism about the title. Way of the superior man? Sounds like some patriarchal bullshit. I’ve always held a strongly feminist viewpoint, and I aim to challenge the ways that men oppress women. I also celebrate my feminine qualities – my sensitivity, receptivity, surrender, and ability to hold space for people. I’ve spent the last couple years in my meditation practice developing these “yin” qualities. But I’ve also become more curious about what a healthy “yang” looks like. This book is a promising step towards answering that question for me. And I found his ideas interesting enough that I want to share them with my friends – men, women, and nonbinary/genderqueer/other – to see what they think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deida opens the book with the explanation that when he uses the words “man” and “woman” he’s referring to people with masculine and feminine core energies, not the two genders or sexes per se. He asserts that about 80% of men have a “masculine core”, 10% have a “feminine core”, and 10% are “balanced/neutral”. Couples may of course consist of men with feminine cores, women with masculine cores, or any number of combinations. He gives further nuance that this might change over time. Even though I dislike making generalizations or normative statements about men and women, and welcome challenge to the limitations of his framing of gender, I’ll use his convention when explaining his ideas. In a future post I might make some more precise caveats about the nebulosity/constructedness/multidimensionality of gender and sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of his core ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A man’s gifts are directness, decisiveness, humor, and loving presence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A man should work through his fears in order to give his full gift and bring more love into the world&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The priority of the masculine should be the mission that leads towards freedom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The priority of the feminine, in men and women, is the flow of love in relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A man should always lean just beyond his edge, where he can feel his fears the most. He shouldn’t fall into an overly difficult, self aggrandizing path which uses arrogance/dissociation to numb away one’s fears. He also shouldn’t fall into comfort and security. Thus he should be neither lazy nor aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Men should meet with their friends once a week to challenge each other to be better.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Recently I’ve participated in men’s circles that are mostly about being emotionally vulnerable with other men. I found these valuable, but Deida suggests a different approach: instead of just giving each other emotional support, men’s circles should be about challenging your male friends to face their fears and take action on things they’re stuck on. “Good friends should not tolerate medicority in one another,” he says. “If you are at your edge, your men friends should respect that, but not let you off the hook. They should honor your fears, and, in love, continue to goad you beyond them, without pushing you”.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to cultivate polarization (sexual attraction in a couple), the masculine partner should lean into their masculine qualities, and the feminine partner should lean into their feminine qualities. There’s some other relationship advice given in this book that I’d like to treat with more nuance than I have time for, but I did find it partially relevant to my own dating experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This book also presents a compelling view about how living in the world and following desire can lead to spiritual development. The core idea is that you follow each desire to completion, gradually maturing in the depth of what you are seeking. As long as you’re living at the edge of your fears, this will eventually push you towards greater freedom in the form of spiritual attainments like overcoming the fear of death and seeing through the ego.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What inspired me most about this book is the idea that the power of masculinity is to look fear square in the face with love, and to do the thing that you want to do and know is right even if it’s scary. I’ve been avoiding writing for a long time because I’m afraid of being criticized, afraid of pissing people off, afraid of sounding like an idiot, afraid of being mediocre. This book pushed me to commit to writing more, starting with this book review. I decided to write it with two days notice, insisting that it be published by the end of the working day whether I like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some open questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do women feel about this book? What is the equivalent book from the feminine point of view?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does healthy masculinity mean in the context of a patriarchal society?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to my friend Max Langenkamp for recommending me this book, for his brotherhood, and for challenging me to be a better man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">I picked up this book with some skepticism about the title. Way of the superior man? Sounds like some patriarchal bullshit. I’ve always held a strongly feminist viewpoint, and I aim to challenge the ways that men oppress women. I also celebrate my feminine qualities – my sensitivity, receptivity, surrender, and ability to hold space for people. I’ve spent the last couple years in my meditation practice developing these “yin” qualities. But I’ve also become more curious about what a healthy “yang” looks like. This book is a promising step towards answering that question for me. And I found his ideas interesting enough that I want to share them with my friends – men, women, and nonbinary/genderqueer/other – to see what they think.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Research Orientation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/02/05/research-orientation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research Orientation" /><published>2023-02-05T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-05T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/02/05/research-orientation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/02/05/research-orientation.html">&lt;p&gt;[This is a work in progress post orienting the reader to my research, as I make my research plan and invite feedback and direction from readers who are also interested in the same topic]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m figuring out what I want to work on. I think that I might want to work on problems related to cities and Urbanism, either for a city government or an adjacent organization, but: What kind of city should I be investing my time into understanding and improving? Should it be a big, established city like NYC? Ecovillages? Small to medium sized charter cities in places that will be climate resilient?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the framing of this question comes from my fears of civilizational collapse, but I don’t have a fleshed out model about what I should be concretely worried about, what could go wrong, how will those things impact different cities differently, etc. Should I be preparing to live in an ecovillage that’s mostly self-sustaining when needed, or can a place like NYC be prepared for future climate-related issues (not just disastrous weather events, but climate refugee intake, disruptions to supply chains, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two books I’d like to read on to help me understand this better are Urbanism for a Difficult Future and Megathreats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting question to me is what levels of density can be supported by different technologies and infrastructures? If our future is solar and growing our own food, that can’t support the density of fossil fuels or nuclear.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">[This is a work in progress post orienting the reader to my research, as I make my research plan and invite feedback and direction from readers who are also interested in the same topic]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cities and The Wealth of Nations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/01/06/cities-and-the-wealth-of-nations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cities and The Wealth of Nations" /><published>2023-01-06T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/01/06/cities-and-the-wealth-of-nations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/2023/01/06/cities-and-the-wealth-of-nations.html">&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for 2023 is to write a review of this book. Reading it, I frequently thought, “Wow, this is an extremely interesting idea, I wonder what the economics establishment would say about it if confronted with it directly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention for the review is to distill the insights of the book in a way where I can share them with other economists and see if the ideas hold up to scrutiny. I’d like to turn the claims in this book into a list of testable hypothesis and see if I can falsify them using historical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central idea of the book is that nation states are the wrong unit of analysis for economic life and we would be better off trying to understand economies through the lens of cities. In a forthcoming post I’ll examine her evidence for this argument and what kinds of insights this change in perspective might yield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also talk about her preferred model for understanding development: import replacing, and how that has traditionally interacted with feedback from a local currency, but usually does not within the context of a nation state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/etiennefd&quot;&gt;Étienne Fortier-Dubois&lt;/a&gt; wrote a great review of this which you should check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/your-book-review-cities-and-the-wealth&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I will still write my own review as an exercise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">One of my goals for 2023 is to write a review of this book. Reading it, I frequently thought, “Wow, this is an extremely interesting idea, I wonder what the economics establishment would say about it if confronted with it directly.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Not Bad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art/2015/02/01/not-bad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not Bad" /><published>2015-02-01T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-02-01T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art/2015/02/01/not-bad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art/2015/02/01/not-bad.html">&lt;p&gt;Digital Collage, 2015&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="art" /><summary type="html">Digital Collage, 2015</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RESISTANT(AAAAAA)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/RESISTANT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RESISTANT(AAAAAA)" /><published>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/RESISTANT</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/RESISTANT.html">&lt;p&gt;Mixed media on drywall, 2014&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="art" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Mixed media on drywall, 2014</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Untitled Blue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-blue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Untitled Blue" /><published>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-blue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-blue.html">&lt;p&gt;Mixed media on paper, 2014&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="art" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Mixed media on paper, 2014</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Untitled Purple</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-purple.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Untitled Purple" /><published>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T18:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-purple</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/11/01/untitled-purple.html">&lt;p&gt;Mixed media on paper, 2014&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="art" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Mixed media on paper, 2014</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unitled Green</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/06/01/bad-bad-not-good.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unitled Green" /><published>2014-06-01T19:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-01T19:15:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/art/2014/06/01/bad-bad-not-good</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/art/2014/06/01/bad-bad-not-good.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;untitled-green&quot;&gt;Untitled Green&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboration with Jake Catt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paint on Drywall, 2014&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="art" /><summary type="html">Untitled Green</summary></entry></feed>